ReactJS Overview
===========================
-React is a front-end library for webapplication/site development which is developed by Facebook.
-React is a declarative, efficient, and flexible JavaScript library for building user interfaces.
-you need to have solid knowledge of JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS.


Environment setup
====================
1.	Install nodeJs
2. 	Install any Editor:
		-VSCode is recommended

		-Create your workspace folder anywhere in a system(in any drive)
		-Go to File menu and click on open folder and add your workspace 
		-To open the terminal 
			cltrl+`		: shortcut 
			or
			Go to view menu and click on Intergrated Terminal 			
		-To check nodejs version 
			$node -v 	
3. 	Install create app
		$npm install -g create-react-app		: -g -global 
4.	Create app
		$npx create-react-app my-app
		or
		$create-react-app <learning>

5. 	Change directory
		$cd learning
		$npm start			: to build and run the application
	
6.   	Install Router module 
	$npm install react-router


ReactJS
=================
ReactJS is JavaScript library used for building reusable UI components. According to React official documentation, following is the definition −

React is a library for building composable user interfaces. It encourages the creation of reusable UI components, which present data that changes over time. Lots of people use React as the V in MVC. React abstracts away the DOM from you, offering a simpler programming model and better performance. React can also render on the server using Node, and it can power native apps using React Native. React implements one-way reactive data flow, which reduces the boilerplate and is easier to reason about than traditional data binding.

React Features
=========================
JSX − JSX is JavaScript syntax extension. It isn't necessary to use JSX in React development, but it is recommended.

Components 
================
− React is all about components. You need to think of everything as a component. This will help you maintain the code when working on larger scale projects.

Flux -> Redux
================
Unidirectional data flow and Flux − React implements one-way data flow which makes it easy to reason about your app. Flux is a pattern that helps keeping your data unidirectional.


License − React is licensed under the Facebook Inc. Documentation is licensed under CC BY 4.0.
		